<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>se.sjoerd.DatMan</id>
  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <project_license>GPL-3.0-or-later</project_license>
  <name>Graphs</name>
  <summary>Plot and manipulate data in a breeze</summary>
  <developer_name>Sjoerd Broekhuijsen</developer_name>
  <description>
    <p>
      Graphs is a simple but powerful data manipulation tool developed with the GNOME environment in mind. It opens and plots two-column data files
      which then easily can be manipulated and transformed. Alternatively, data can be generated and plotted from an equation. The transformed data can be saved as .txt file for further use.
    </p>
    <p>
      Graphs can both be used as plotting tool, or as a data manipulation tool. There's an extensive number of options to change the plot layouts including,
      but not limited to the axis labels, the prefered scaling on either axis, the length and width of the ticks used, the thickness of the lines, the linestyle,
      the fonts and more. The plots can be saved in multiple formats, including vector images for further editing in e.g. Inkscape. The data manipulation tools
      include options like:
          </p>
    <ul>
      <li>Selecting and cutting part of the data</li>
      <li>Translation and multiplification of data</li>
      <li>Centering data</li>
      <li>Smoothening data</li>
      <li>Custom transformations using anything that is compatible with the numpy module</li>
    </ul>
    <p>
      Graphs is still in very early development, and a large number of features are still planned. For any future requests or feedback, please file an issue on Github or send
      me an email. 
    </p>
  </description>
  <launchable type="desktop-id">se.sjoerd.DatMan.desktop</launchable>
  <url type="bugtracker">https://github.com/SjoerdB93/Graphs/issues</url>
  <url type="help">https://github.com/SjoerdB93/Graphs/</url>
  <url type="homepage">https://www.sjoerd.se</url>
  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <caption>GIScan settings</caption>
      <image>http://www.sjoerd.se/datman_main.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <caption>GIScan settings</caption>
      <image>http://www.sjoerd.se/datman_equations.png</image>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <caption>GIScan settings</caption>
      <image>http://www.sjoerd.se/datman_light_dark.png</image>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>
  <releases>
    <release version="1.0.3" date="2022-12-16">
      <description>
        <p>Minor update with some bug fixes, next update will focus on adding more options for file imports:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Fixed a bug where files with a special character in the name didn't save</li>
          <li>Fixed a bug where minor ticks would show anyway when ticks were turned off</li>
          <li>Configuration now resets when new options are detected (instead of crashing the application)</li>
          <li>Added an option to allow for duplicate filenames when importing</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.0.2" date="2022-12-15">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>Changed the name of the application to be more in line with the GNOME HIG</li>
          <li>Transformation window can be closed with escape</li>
          <li>Fixed a bug where graph would not plot if any of the values where infinite (e.g. if equation Y = 1/X was plotted)</li>
          <li>Step-size, X-start and X-stop in add-equation window now also handle numpy notation</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.0.1" date="2022-12-15">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>Add equation window can be closed with Esc</li>
          <li>File chooser dialog and preference dialogs are modal (stick to parent window</li>
          <li>Remove arrow from hamburger menu</li>
          <li>Add a placeholder hint to Add equation window name</li>
          <li>Changed saving behaviour to allow saving files without file system access for flatpak</li>
          <li>Fixed a bug in the add equation window where powers were not working</li>
          <li>Fixed a bug in add equation window where duplicate filenames were not detected properly</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="1.0.0" date="2022-12-14">
      <description>
        <ul>
          <li>Initial release</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
  </releases>
  <recommends>
    <control>keyboard</control>
    <control>pointing</control>
  </recommends>
  <content_rating type="oars-1.1"/>
</component>
